now that we know what the reorder buffer
is supposed to look like let's see how
it's used for that we need the reorder
buffer with its commit and issue points
and we need the rest of the processor
that we have already seen the
instruction queue reservation stations
registers and the rat let's say that we
have this add instruction here in the
instruction queue so now we want to see
what happens once we start issuing this
all the way to once we eventually Commit
This instruction in a that now has a
reorder buffer so let's first see what
happens on instruction issue as before
when we didn't have the reorder buffer
we get a free reservation station and we
put our instruction in it now that we do
have a reorder buffer we will also get
one of those unlike reservation station
where we just need a free one it doesn't
matter which one it is here we need to
get the entry that is the next one at
the issue point so our instruction will
go here in the reorder buffer that of
course also means that our issue point
will now move and points to the next
entry in the reorder buffer so now we
have seven instructions that have been
issued and have not yet committed
another thing that we had to do when we
were issuing instructions in maso's
algorithm is that the rat entry for R1
the destination register of the
instruction needed to be point pointed
to the reservation station for the
instruction we will still need to do
this pointing but instead of the
reservation station now we point the r
entry to the Rob entry for the
instruction that means that this R entry
will be now instead of pointing to the
reservation
station be pointing to this entry here
so overall at the end of the cycle when
we issue this instruction we will occupy
a reservation station
with the values that we found for these
registers we will make the r point to
the Rob six entry and in this entry we
will say that R1 will need to be written
for this instruction and we don't still
have the value so the done bit is zero
here for this instruction now this ad
here might wait for operants to become
ready and that happens exactly as before
with tomasulo's algorithm we just
capture results that we need and we are
ready to dispatch once we have all the
operants eventually the ad has all the
things that it needs to dispatch and the
dispatching works exactly the same as
before so we check whether the operants
are ready and when they are we send the
instruction for execution but now we can
also free the reservation station as
soon as we dispatch previously with
tomasulo's algorithm we needed to wait
for the reservation station release all
the way until this instruction
broadcasts its result
that was needed because the reservation
station serves as the name for the
result now that the name for the result
is the Rob entry we no longer need the
reservation stations to play that role
so the reservation station now does only
its primary job which is wait for
operant and capture them and then figure
out which instructions to dispatch after
that the reservation station for the
instruction is done so we can free it so
now our at exit Utes and carries with it
the tag of Rob 6 which is the name for
its result eventually it produces a
result